Federico Matias Rodriguez

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain



federicomatias.rodriguez@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/federico-matias-rodriguez



https://asteriscos.github.io

Summary

Full Stack Developer React, NodeJS, C#, PHP

8+ years of experience as a full stack developer, designing web interfaces, dashboards, server-side apps and features, improving response times and search engine optimization.

I would describe myself as someone who loves challenges and growth opportunities. Results driven, enthusiast, pragmatic, team player and above all always giving my best not only technically, but also as a human being.

Experience



Senior Web Application Developer

Wazuh, Inc.

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

Designing and developing dashboards & web apps for an international open source project as Wazuh's magnitude was very enriching, not only at a technical point of view but also by being a member and giving support to the open source community.



Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

Bytemaiden

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 (7 months)



Lead Web Developer

Data IQ

Feb 2018 - Jun 2020 (2 years 5 months)

Lead Web Developer

.Net - NodeJS

MongoDB

ReactJS

Jest

QlikView & Qlik Sense Integrations, Extensions, Mashups

APIs, process automation

Planning product development and timelines. Team coordination. Interface between the dev team and several other internal and external company areas.

I was a lone pioneer in a brand new area, which has as primary objective to develop customized solutions to out-of-the-box needs. Later, due to hard work, innovation and promising results, what was a experimental one-man job became a stable team of 4 spearheaded by me.

Designed and developed a licensing system that allowed the company to expand revenue possibilities. Standardized and automated compatibility reports to prevent issues in every Qlik Sense release. Led and trained junior programmers not only in good programming practices but also helped them develop soft skills.

Full Stack Developer

emBlue

Jun 2015 - Jul 2017 (2 years 2 months) Full Stack Developer

- C#, jQuery, ASP.NET Web App / Web Services development
- NHibernate
- Web layout
- Database administration and development using SQL Server
- Benchmark and performance improvement

Developed the web interface of the company's star application, as well as serveral server-side features.

Removed redundant requests to the server, reducing 30% the response time.

Optimized SQL queries improving data retrieval delays by 25%.

Developed web tools for the customer support team, which led to happier customers and a less stressed customer support area.

537∕5 Full Stack Developer

SD Technology, Buenos Aires Apr 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 2 months) PHP Full Stack Developer

- PHP Development and maintenance of web app
- Maintenance of company PHP and Javascript internal libraries
- Web layout HTML4/HTML5 CSS2/CSS3
- Maintenance of internal applications
- Database administration and development using SQL Server & MySQL products
- Benchmark and performance improvement
- Customer support, problem solving

Being part of a small web development team allowed me to experience the whole creative process of sketching from scratch, designing and developing an e-commerce and a CMS.

Designed a pre-rendering caching system, cutting down rendering times by half.

Developed a small vainilla javascript library to handle image galleries.

Simplified the web apps installation by implementing a PHP template pattern.

Full Stack Developer Full Stack D

SD Technology, Buenos Aires Dec 2011 - Feb 2013 (1 year 3 months) PHP Full Stack Developer

- PHP Development and maintenance of web app
- Maintenance of company PHP and Javascript internal libraries
- Web layout HTML4/HTML5 CSS2/CSS3
- Maintenance of internal applications
- Database administration and development using SQL Server & MySQL products
- Benchmark and performance improvement
- Customer support, problem solving

Education

***∪TN Universidad Tecnológica Nacional**

2011 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

- in Node.js: Microservices LinkedIn
- in Node.js: Security LinkedIn
- in Migrating from REST to GraphQL LinkedIn
- in Building Modern Projects with React LinkedIn
- AWS and React: Creating Full-Stack Apps LinkedIn
- Learning Amazon Web Services (AWS) for Developers (2018) LinkedIn
- React Native Ecosystem and Workflow LinkedIn
- in React: Server-Side Rendering LinkedIn

Skills

React.js • Node.js • C# • Web Development • Web Applications • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Web Service • Search Engine Optimization (SEO) • Responsive Web Design • Front-end Development